Times like these call for a Big Lebowski.
The Big Lebowski is a comedy, crime film directed by Joel Coen.
Jeffrey 'The Dude' Lebowski, a Los Angeles slacker who only wants to bowl and drink White Russians, is mistaken for another Jeffrey Lebowski, a wheelchair-bound
millionaire, and finds himself dragged into a strange series of events involving nihilists, adult film producers, ferrets, errant toes, and large sums of money.
The Dude, played by Jeff Bridges.
Walter Sobchak, played by John Goodman.
Maude Lebowski, played by Julianne Moore.
Donny, played by Steve Buscemi.
The Big Lebowski, played by David Huddleston.
Brandt, played by Philip Seymour Hoffman.
The Big Lebowski () is a 1998 crime comedy film written, directed, produced and co-edited by Joel and Ethan
Coen, and starring Jeff Bridges, John Goodman, Julianne Moore, Steve Buscemi and John Turturro.
It follows the life of Jeffrey "The Dude" Lebowski, a Los Angeles slacker and avid bowler who is assaulted as a result
of mistaken identity, then learns that a millionaire who shares the same name was the intended victim.
The film is loosely inspired by the work of Raymond Chandler.
Joel Coen stated, "We wanted to do a Chandler kind of story – how it moves episodically and deals with the characters trying to unravel a mystery, as well as having a
hopelessly complex plot that's ultimately unimportant." The original score was composed by Carter Burwell, a longtime collaborator of the Coen brothers.
The Big Lebowski was produced by Working Title Films and distributed by Gramercy Pictures in the
United States and Canada and by PolyGram Filmed Entertainment internationally.
It received mixed reviews at the time of its release.
Reviews have since become largely positive and the film has garnered a cult following, noted for its
eccentric characters, comedic dream sequences, idiosyncratic dialogue and eclectic soundtrack.
In 2014, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically or aesthetically significant."
The film explores themes of vietnam veteran, white
russian, bowling, carpet, nihilism.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and intense.